Everybody wants to pick winners and losers like is it gonna be the apple or is it gonna be the potato right?
Like which one of these are we doing?
And I'm saying the future actually looks like gazpacho, right?
Like it's just gonna everything's gonna be in there and it's all together
I worry right now that to be totally honest and I've said this elsewhere
We're seeing a whole lot of my space and very little Facebook and the answer to who will win is none of the people currently on the field
Hi everyone, welcome to Unchained. You're no hype resource for all things crypto. I'm your host Laura Shin
The stablecoin race is heating up in a big way with both big and small players getting in
I had a conversation with Austin Campbell about how it might shake out and was surprised by what he said
When stablecoins become integrated he believes the system could end up all being a lot less decentralized and censorship resistance
And the ideals that crypto has long espoused
Austin seems to think that tech innovation will matter less
And financial regulation would matter more and could even prevent disruption from happening to the same extent as has happened in other industries
This sort of echoes what Jim Bianca was saying in the recent interview
I did with him that regulation will end up being the kingmakers
I do wish I had managed to ask Austin about one thing
He talks about how the fact that ethereum validators didn't censor anything related to the bibit hack
She was that ethereum isn't ready for prime time when it comes to real world assets
I suspect a number of you would find those to be fighting words
My main question is that it could become not just a slippery slope
But a full-on quagmire if ethereum were to censor in those instances, especially for less clear-cut cases
I was also surprised when Austin called out a couple of blockchains that are yes in the top 25
But not part of the hype cycle and he said that he thought they had the potential to be better solutions than ethereum for real world assets
At this moment in time, I'm skeptical of those claims even as I'm aware that a lot could change in the next five or ten years
Either way, Austin is engaging as always
Let us know what you think about the show by commenting on an episode or on any platform or by writing us a review
enjoy
At unchanged we believe the future should be decentralized and that includes our data
That's why we use walrus the fast dynamic verifiable data layer
Learn more about the platform that's powering our future at walrus.xyz
One early Bitcoiner sold 30,000 BTC to soon missing out on over a billion dollars
Don't want to make the same estate with Zappobank eligible members can get instant cash without selling their Bitcoin
Check out zappobank.com/unchained for more
Hands up everyone we've got exciting news bits and bits our macro meets crypto show is
Officially spinning off into its own podcast feed youtube channel and X account if you've been enjoying the deep dives into interest rates
Monetary policy and how they intersect with the crypto markets make sure to follow bits and bits wherever you get your podcasts on
YouTube and on X
You'll find the links to YouTube X and other podcast platforms in the show notes if you're watching this
There's a QR code on screen
We'll be posting here for a few more weeks, but starting in September bits and bits will launch on its own feed
For now, we will publish longer clips from the show on those accounts
Remember go to the show notes now and subscribe to bits and bits. That's bits plus sign Bips spelled B I P S on
YouTube X and wherever you get your podcasts
Welcome Austin
Hey Laura, thank you for having me back
This week we saw multiple announcements that show that the stablecoin race is heating up in a big way
First on Monday fortune reported that stripe in conjunction with crypto BC firm paradigm is
developing a layer one blockchain called tempo for stablecoin payments and on Tuesday circle announced
We'll be launching its own stablecoin focused blockchain arc
And this is on top of several other stablecoin chains are in the works like plasma stable codecs
Um, so before we just like go into the details on all of these different chains
Just explain why it is that you think we're seeing so many stablecoin focused blockchains and like why we even need
Chains that are focused on stablecoins
Yeah, so I think
You know to give what I will describe is called the median corporate response to many of these things
It's that people themselves are using stablecoins for things if you look at things like stripe if you look at circle
This is obviously the reason these businesses are in existence and interested is paying for things with dollars through the form of like electronic money
So it's not surprising they're looking at these implementations and trying to build ones where they capture the value
If you want to be financially nihilistic about it
The answer is to why they're doing it as people appear to give the money to do it, right?
Like many of these l ones have been very successful tokens have gone up
Right if you want to be financially idealistic about it
I think the thing you would say is that most if not all but probably most
Of the modern blockchain implementations are insufficient for tokenization of real-world assets
Because they just haven't grappled with a lot of the tension that comes with the decentralized ethos versus the
Fact that the real world itself is actually very centralized in many ways
And so people are trying to build custom solutions that can bridge that gap and be a little bit more effective
Now which one of those do I believe some of all of it?
And so
Um, what is it about a chain that's focused specifically on stablecoin payments that is necessary or or maybe it's not
Um, but that you know these players seem to think is necessary that isn't offered by existing public blockchains
Okay, so I would say maybe the best example of this
I I was back at jp morgan in the day when we were thinking about what waiter became onyx
And one of the things you think about with financial applications is what are the transaction preferences of the underlying people and what are they using it for?
So like a good example of the critique of the architecture of ethereum that I think is meaningful
Is if we were to try to put all payments on ethereum
And it's lunchtime
And i'm standing in line at a deli and i'm trying to buy a sandwich and i've got to tap to pay and when I do that
I pay some tiny gas fee and stablecoins go to the other side
And taylor swift decides lunchtime is a great time to drop a new album and people are buying it at the same time
I don't want to pay a hundred dollar gas fee to buy my sandwich
right and so
Transaction preferences are not monolithic right like the speed and level of security
That you need is definitely diffuse like trying to rush to buy a limited edition nft versus buying a sandwich versus
I don't know clearing up 50 billion dollar repo trade
All have very different parameters to them
And so it one on one level it may make sense for there to be certain very payment focused chains
That have very predictable and low fees so that you don't end up
In a situation where like nobody can buy lunch because of taylor swift not not an insult to the swifties right just a conflict on the platform
too
I think there is also the issue that you run into there of things like spam resilience and like why do you have blockchain fees to begin with
And very purpose oriented chains where maybe you can only do push payments eliminate a lot of that behavior because like if you want to spam me by sending me many small amounts of money
I guess sure thanks
Um, and so less features is sometimes more for some of these chains
The last part and this I think is very under discussed in the blockchain world
But like having dealt a lot with stable coins. I think about it a lot
Is the security component of that?
And the example I use to describe this we can use stable coins, but I'll use something that's hopefully a little bit funnier for the audience
Is if we tokenize a lot of real assets so that people can you know buy them and pay for them on chain
And one of the things we tokenize is title for house if somebody's grandma's house is tokenized
And the nft gets stolen by the north koreans. What do you do?
Right and by the way, there's a there's a small subset of people in krypto who will say well
I guess the north koreans own the house now and my answer to that is that cannot possibly be how it works
Right because the us military has strong views on the north koreans attempting to move into somebody's house
Um, and it's not going to happen. This is back to my point of like the blockchain may be decentralized, but the real world is not
Okay, so now the question becomes how do you get it back and to your point on blockchain architecture
The first answer i'm going to get from people is well issuers will have freeze and seize capability and therefore they can take the house back
And I say ah, yes, that's good
Unless it was the issuer that got hacked and compromised and if that's the case, what do we do next? And the answer there is
Really either
You need a controls framework and validator set that will individually revert transactions and keep things somewhat permissioned
Which is how a lot of the banks and payments companies think about this
So if you look at the architecture in a lot of the bank chains, there is transaction reversibility
Or you're going to need to drop an entirely new smart contract
Repugiate the old one and essentially replace all the tokens as of a point of time
And the problem with that is if you're doing that second approach you essentially can't have DeFi in its current form
Because if that happens to like usdc
I invite all of our listeners to think about what happens to all like the usdc eats or like usdc curve
Like amm pools and what happens to all the borrow end protocols when circle repudiates its old smart contract and drops new ones
Okay
Well, so
Then i'd be so interested to hear because like we're entering this phase where clearly there's me a ton of competition
And so i'd love to just go through one by one and hear what you think are kind of the advantages and disadvantages of these different chains
So let's start with the tempo one, which is the one that stripe is doing apparently with paradigm
And it's actually going to be led by matt vong portion reported
Who's also staying at paradigm at the same time that's sort of like
I know this isn't exactly apples to apples
But like it reminds me of like a jacked or c type of thing like i'm just gonna like lead a whole bunch of different things
But i'd be curious to hear you know what you think are the main advantages that stripe would have or tempo would have and disadvantages
So I actually think the main advantage there is literally stripe
And what I mean by that is the current world largely does not exist on blockchains
Right if we look at the amount of money flowing through blockchains blockchains people get very excited and it feels large
When numbers of annual settlement get into the trillions
But I will remind everybody that international wire transfers alone
Are 1.25 quadrillion annually is an estimate a number so large it sounds like my 10 year old made it up
And so the amount of activity on blockchains is still extremely small
Stripes has a large and significant payments processing business using traditional rails
So if stripe also has a blockchain and they could effectively do the sandwich that is to say now people can pay for things on chain
And if the receiving person on the other side wants dollars in a bank account
Stripe is going to be one of the entities that could be very good at functioning as a bridge
Pun intended given their acquisition
Between these two sort of spaces and that to me is probably the biggest advantage stripe has
Number two boy do they have a lot of customers and specifically customers in the merchant space if you look at who stripe deals with
And so if we're talking about something that could scale
Something that can be used by regular two legged people without being like deep technological experts and something that can exist in both worlds
Stripes got a pretty decent shot at it right like there may be better
But anybody better is probably an even more scaled financial institution like is JP morgan going to launch a public l1
If not stripes in pretty good shape and by the way, you know, if you're watching for
The areas in the coal mine of if this sort of thing is working
Look for what the other payments companies do in response or to evolve their own platform offerings
So like the visas of the world the master cards of the world pay pal who already has their own stable quick
Oh, okay
Interesting
Well, we'll circle back to that in a moment. Um, so now let's talk about arc, which is circles new blockchain that they announced
And um that one they announced, you know around like right when they did their earnings report
Um, I'm sure you saw like people like adam cochrin tweeted
This isn't an l1 and it's offensive to call it such
It's a consortium chain of private pre-approved validators who even have permission to refund transactions via dispute protocols
And he goes on
Um, so yeah, I'm curious to hear what you think are the advantages and disadvantages of that
Yeah, so I I would say adam is at war with reality
With his comments and what I mean by that is if you've ever worked in payments things like dispute resolution chargebacks, etc
Are like name of the game type stuff for two different reasons
One is if you don't have that functionality
You're going to be an open forum for like fraudsters scammers bad actors
And essentially provide an extremely poor experience depending on which side you come down on
On either to your buyers and sellers and people are just not going to use it
Right again back to the real world not being decentralized laura if you're a vendor and i'm your customer and I buy something from you
It's broken and I want to get a refund now what right? This is the kind of thing payment processors have to deal with two
In many jurisdictions there are legal obligations around this
So if you say well your blockchain shouldn't have this functionality somebody's sitting in a payments role
Just here's a giant sucking sound knowing all the money that they're going to be paying people without the ability to get it back
Right, so again, the real world is not decentralized either. I got the product or I didn't it's a binary state of a physical object
That is what it is
Circle specific like design
I think they need a consortium because the reality is circle doesn't have many direct customers
If you look at the number of people who have circle accounts, it's not that high if you look at the distribution of usdc
There's mainly one source of it and that's a little company. We've probably heard of called coinbase
And so they do not have the advantage stripe has of tons of native on boarded customers who can use things one-to-one
So if you're a company like circle and you're not going to do a consortium, my next question is how the heck are you going to acquire all your customers?
I think they're kind of trapped into doing that, but then that becomes
Why is circle in particular going to win at this and
You know, I'll be honest and say I'm quite skeptical there
Right like circle having a revenue sharing agreement with coinbase and having to build a consortium model in that fashion
It's probably good
For like coinbase and coin bases distribution may work
But if you're trying to get like banks and merchants and payment processors on there
But most of the interest revenue is being shared with coinbase, they're all just going to say now
Yeah, yeah where I was leading to next was, you know, when I looked at tempo my immediate
My immediate thought was oh in a way this competes with um bases Shopify integration
um
But you know, I so I
Kind of I can't remember. I think I like wrote this somewhere
Or or at least it's just the thought that I've had and and I'm not the originator of this
I think I've seen other people say
That looking back it kind of feels like coinbase probably should have acquired to circle
Because like or maybe you disagree with me, but like in my head i'm a little bit like
You know the net like for for coinbase to own the distribution and
Like like in this hypothetical world if they own the distribution and usdc
Then I feel like they would have been better positioned to compete against stripe
But um, anyway, so regardless of you know, you can answer either the the real world as it exists or the hypothetical
But be curious for how you think this competition will go down between um
Stripe and coinbase slash base slash Shopify
I worry right now that to be totally honest and i've said this elsewhere
We're seeing a whole lot of my space and very little facebook and the expert who will win is none of the people currently on the field
Um, and the reason I say that is again having come from the very large banking world and seeing the scale of money transfers
You know, I kind of look at things like stripe and coinbase and spotify and i'm like, oh, that's a cute little side business
You've got there and I don't mean that in like a negative way
Right, like they've actually done an extremely good job
If you look at like what the leadership team at coinbase has done or like how stripe has built their business
I actually think the world of what they've done in that regard
But i'm also saying that tells you what a titan some of the largest financial entities are that they could have done so well
And it's like congrats your two percent of the size of jp morgan
and so
My worry is that over time
You're essentially going to have somebody very large come over the top
With a complete international payments franchise because if you look at fx volumes
What happens if standard chartered launches stable coins in an elwad or like doge a bag or like jp morgan and not
token i spec depots right but like actual proper stable coins that people can use permissionless
You know and then integrate into the rails of those companies
I would be terrified
As some of the current competitors that i'm just going to get trucked by those offerings
Because like if you think coinbase has a lot of customers go look at some of the megabags globally
And and so when i look at this i look at all of them and think they're in a race against time
Of some of the big guys either cycling out their current management for younger people or that management getting the punchline on what's going on and getting into the game
because
You know tech is used to network effects that come from like social stickiness, but that's not how network effects and finance work
That's largely liquidity and yield driven right like great example. It'll be trivial for me to build
Like a relatively significantly productive
You know call it asset gathering business in the money market space if i'm willing to pay
An above market interest rate by just burning capital on my part
But the problem is those companies or excuse me those customers are not sticky the moment i stop doing that
They'll leave and go to other options like it's a constant dynamic rebalancing
And what it means is the really big players who have distribution and can cross subsidize are very hard to compete against
That's why we can't like from 2008 on get rid of these sippy backs
Okay, so in a moment we're going to talk a little bit more about how this competition will play out
But first a quick word from the sponsor to make this show possible
At unshamed we care about the future of decentralization
So it only made sense for our media content to be decentralized. That's why we use walrus
It's the fast dynamic and verifiable data layer for on-chain builders
And it's not just data management walrus ties directly into smart contracts
Unlocking new possibilities for programmable content delivery subscriptions and community engagement
So as we imagine what decentralized media can become walrus is the tech we trust to help build it
Learn more at walrus.xyz
Selling your bitcoin just to get cash one early bitcoiner did and missed out on over a billion dollars
With zapobank you can access up to one million dollars instantly without selling a single set
Eligible zapobank members can borrow up to 40 percent of their bitcoin's value
No stress. No selling. No buying back in use it for what matters most
Your dream home your child's education a getaway or that can't miss investment with bitcoin backed loans
You're in control set your installments and repay in bitcoin or us dollars your choice
Enjoy competitive rates zero fees flexible terms and no penalties for early repayment
And your bitcoin stays safe. Never re-hypothecated
Relent or pooled it's securely held until your loan is repaid check them out at zapobank.com/unchained
So I want to um
Continue with with some of these other chains and then we'll go back to this competition question
Um, you know, we have in the works this plasma blockchain. We have another one stable
Uh, quote code. I you know, we don't have to go through all of them, but you know, some of them have like
Pretty heavy hitting investors or teams behind them. You know tether
Um is obviously involved in uh plasma so or or stable or the invested in plasma
And then they're they're building stable. So can you just talk a little bit about how you think about those chains and how they might compete in this environment?
Yeah, so one thing i'll say, you know, I said this earlier and i'll remind everybody again transaction preferences are not monolithic
I think what we're looking at right now is a landscape where we assume all of these people are competing against each other may be wrong
Right because like to give a like metaphor to make it accessible to people. I live in new york city
All of like the yankies and the mats and the nicks and the nets and the giants and the jets are professional sports teams here
But they don't all compete against each other right like there is competition within the subsets
But if the giants are playing the nicks something has gone terribly wrong
And what I mean by that is if you look at where tether is used as a good example
Almost all of the major usage of tethers in one of two places
It's either in crypto trading or in emerging markets payments
Right and that's the truth. Nobody is using tether on shore in the united states
To like pay for things with credit cards or like go to the bodega or something like that or if they are
It's like de minimis amounts right on the other hand
USDC is more frequently used for that in the united states
You can get literally a coin base debit card if you have a coin base account and have USDC in your account
Go tap to pay with things in the united states
They're like different segments of the payments market, which is bigger than people think and I think what you're going to find
with many of these efforts with the blockchains
Is that the user base and the core activity of the people involved are going to drive
Where they focus their efforts
So if something like what tether is doing becomes a swift replacement for euro dollar style payments, especially in the global south
You know, especially among merchants and consumers. I would be zero surprised
But does that really compete with what like stripe is trying to do honestly? No
In fact, they may interact with each other in a way that creates more market opportunities for them that if neither exist it
Right or even only one existed
So as I think about competition
The traditional space is so large
And many of these efforts are relatively like attached to current things that have been sort of niche expansions that I think most of them
You know, a little bit like the early internet laura are supportive of each other by existing because they're just drawing more attention to the space
I really think all of them are eating away like tiny piranhas right at the behemoth that is like visa or mastercard
Okay, so, you know earlier when you talked about how you felt like a big bank
You know, would kind of look at at any of these efforts in scoff. I mean the
History of technology is littered with
Incumbents that could not disrupt themselves or or would not
I mean just even in our lifetimes, you know, like
Blockbuster borders codac
You know, I mean this has happened just so many times so
What what makes you think that?
Traditional things could really, you know be competitive in this area
So I'm gonna point out something important about what you just said about all these disruptors. How many of those were financial companies?
I mean none of them but
Finance is different and what I mean by that is tech is usually not the driver of results, right? Like
I worked at a bank that on day one in training the CEO came on and said we have bailed out the us government
Twice in the past hundred years and I expect you to behave accordingly
Right and what I would say is finance is a scale game
Not a technology game and often the technology matters less than people think so long as it is sufficient to get the job done
Right like whether you get the best price or not on a bond trade
Often has very little to do with whether JP Morgan or gold mid-saxes or Morgan Stanley's technology is incrementally better
It's actually the risk management judgment of the traders
Right and so
The reason that I look at this and sort of as both a banking person and a blockchain person
Say sometimes I think people are missing the punchline
Is it's a very sort of tech thing to want to compete on the verticals that they understand without understanding the verticals that actually lead to results
so
I'm a little bit more skeptical of
These results from companies early on leading to massive restructuring of the total financial system
I think the area that's most amenable to what you just said is payments because payments right now have a lot of market structure problems that are
Let's be honest partially regulatory more than technology like bags if they wanted
They're not going to let's be clear bags are terrible at working with each other
But if they wanted to all of them could just put together a shared private database to do instant payments globally right now
Right. There's not a technological blocker out that there's a willingness blocker and so disruption there. I think is very meaningful
But bags are giant entities that do way more than just payments and I like one of the things I very much always caution people about is do not generalize
From your local circumstances as somebody who is like a retail customer or a bank to what the business of the actual bank is
From any of these banks the retail customers are like a small
Like pocket of the world and not an unimportant one
But like if JP morgan's entire consumer business like chase vanish tomorrow. They're still a gigantic financial institution
right and so
You know what i'm trying to drive home here is this is a very complex multi variable
Problem of which tech is only one pillar
And that's why I think I bring a little bit more skepticism on massive transformation there
Also because there's a coordination problem right like if somebody adopts a method of payment, but the guy on the other side hasn't
You you can't transact
And so it really is the global liquidity network that matters. So I think
rather than the traditional tech model of like
incumbents being disrupted and being completely destroyed and then a new thing rises and then they'll eventually get disrupted and destroyed
And then a new thing right like the sort of sharp thin
model of technological development
Finance has been significantly more iterative
It looks like steps where everybody gets dragged along because you need that network effect to transact with money
And I I really think this is an extremely important point in this l1 debate that people are having and I think a lot of investors are going to be
Very disappointed having invested evaluations that assume total market disruption if things go well
And then they find out that actually no in this space you don't eat the market the market eventually eats you
So okay, so I just need to understand then
How do you think this is actually going to play out like who are going to be the big winners and losers because it sounds like you're saying
We're seeing all these up starts and none of them is really going to succeed the way that people are betting
And it almost sounds like you're saying that the banks are going to be the big winners
Which like if that's the case then satoshi is rolling over in their grave if they're in a grave
um, so
That that would I don't think people would
I don't think people would be if that were really the outcome here. I think people in krypton would quit
They would be like this is not what I signed up for
So I'll start. I think the biggest winner will be consumers, right?
Let us not forget there are a lot of forms of technological development that maybe any individual company doesn't capture it
But the net benefit to like consumers and the economy is huge
So I do think the number one winner here is going to be consumers because like let me remind everybody of the current deal that you have with a bank
Okay, and uh, this is from the retail perspective
And by the way, I
Almost 100 odds you're getting ripped off right now because here's what they do give us deposits
We're going to go lend those deposits and take a ton of risk
If it goes well
We're going to say we're awesome and pay ourselves giant bonuses
If it goes poorly
The bank goes bankrupt and you might lose all of your money and by the way, we don't pay you any interest
Right like again
Like if you're a vc in this space or like you're just somebody who's in the stock market
Imagine I pitch you an investment that is like you give me, you know a hundred thousand dollars
And if it does great, I keep all the profits
But if it goes down you take the losses
That's what your bank is actually doing to you with most deposit accounts in the united states of america
It's deranged
And so I think breaking that paradigm with things like stablecoins that create better options and better networks is incredibly valuable
Even if any individual company does not accrue the gains
Consumers writ large and the economy will accrue those gains
And then you are taking less risk and probably getting paid interest on safer deposits
This is good for everybody right now
People using our system for payments are giving a giant subsidy to certain subtypes of borrowers
And by the way, since banks don't retain a lot of mortgages
It's not like the average person buying a home. Those go generally into the market to get securitized
It's like project loans commercial real estate like certain kinds of structured finance basically billionaires are getting a subsidy
So breaking that I think is good
Now number two
Do I think the banks are going to be winners writ large as a segment? Yes
Specific banks within that
Oh, is there a lot of danger here right like
I would tell you I think a lot of banks are going to consolidate
Or get disaggregated by the trend of crypto right like right now the modern bank is this super dense entity
You know a little bit like crypto exchanges where we talk about decentralization and then created the most centralized financial entities possible
Right like your bank is handling your lending
And your deposit account and your payments and selling you investment products, right? It's like the all singing all dancing thing
And I think one of the things crypto will do is unbundle the banks so the answer is to where the winners will emerge
Is who understands this unbundling effect correctly and either?
remains bundled by transforming their business offerings to become more modular
or
Actually picks one of those niches and dominates it and that is why i'm saying i'm skeptical blockchain natives will dominate
Now that's not a statement. There's not value for blockchain natives
But i'm saying everybody wants to pick winners and losers like is it going to be the apple or is it going to be the potato
Right like which one of these are reviewing and i'm saying the future actually looks like gazpacho
Right like it's just going to everything's going to be in there and it's all together
All right. Well
One other question is so i'm sure you know that
People are going on tv and saying that ethereum is the staple coin chain
And I was just curious what you thought this particular activity would have on
You know this narrative for ethereum
Yeah, so I I actually said this at an event yesterday put on by the ethereum foundation
Um, I don't think ethereum is ready for prime time for real world asset issuance
For the exact reasons that I just previously described
Like we just witnessed with the bibit hack that the ethereum validator said is currently in a place where they're not really willing to do things
About significant exploits and so I would ask the entire ethereum community. Let's assume a worst-case scenario happens in tether or circles private keys get compromised
And a hacker is now in control of the smart contract out of the area for usdc or usdt
Including all of their freeze and seize capabilities
What do you do?
Right like what are you doing with your hands? What is your game plan at that point because it's going to break
Everything on that chain and until we have
Significantly more mature risk management tooling around like the ethereum product it is not ready for prime time
And like again as a financial practitioner. I've heard so many people tell me well, this has never happened before it's not a risk and i'm like
This is how people blow up non-stop like you've just told me what I heard from long-term capital management
You've just told me what we heard from the mbs people you've just told me what I heard at jp morgan when the london will was going
I'm like, oh, it's fine. There can't be a problem
Okay, the fact that a risk has not explicitly happened yet is not a statement that it won't happen in the future
And so
There are design and functionality things that are like well known in traditional finance that could have stopped a lot of these hacks
And so people are going to look at them and be like if you don't build them
We are going to I don't know go watch it l1 that has these capabilities
Which may partially explain some of the trend we're seeing right now
Right like to give a really trivial one if people remember the mango markets hack with avi
Right
A lot of the issue there was that mango markets was lending against spot prices and illiquid tokens
Which is insane
Right if i'm on a repo desk at a major bank and I have something that just ripped a hundred
Percent in the past 20 minutes and somebody comes to me to borrow against it
I'm not using that price to loan to them. I'm going to take like a 48 hour trailing average and a bare minimum
And be like yeah, I'll loan you but like a 10
LTV on this current price like stop it right and
Again, these are very common things that are understood
So really the dialogue between both sides needs to improve because again
There are real technological benefits to open access consensus ledgers that is very important that it will matter
But if you can't build in some of these risk management frameworks, right?
We're just going to end up in a point where it's like we have two equally broken systems talking past each other
Okay
So this is so interesting because you know here I
Started the conversation by noting all all this activity
And and the thesis and tell me if i'm wrong your thesis
Is that forget about all these like upstarts?
It's going to be the big banks that that win the day or not just banks asset managers payments companies
Some of the upstarts my thesis is that people like to think of markets like
literal financial markets in the form of discrete winners and losers as though like it's you know
You know building a wins or building b wins. Okay, but okay, so then which of the upstarts you think are best positioned to capitalize?
Okay, so i'll say some things that I think will probably surprise people here
Um, especially given the tenor of some of my previous comments one bitcoin
Obviously there the credible neutrality is very important bitcoin has never said i'm trying to be a regulated
Asset used for these things i'm trying to be like extra sovereign money or you know, however you would term it
And they're doing a good job of that. So in bitcoin's case if the north korean steel it somebody goes
Yeah, they're the legal owner now that's kind of working as intended
Which tells you there are some things that will be very good for and some things it's unusable for but I think there's product market fit there
I think stablecoins have definitely been a winner
right like
How we have designed getting units of currency onto a blockchain and moving around dollar tokens is a big win
Now does that mean circle or tether or the long term winner? No, but stablecoins is a product
Definitely. Yes, they are here to stay
Um specific upstarts within that space look coinbase has gotten big enough that they're going to be something
Either they get acquired by somebody gigantic or continue growing themselves. I like their odds
Right circle a little bit less clear because if you look at money supply versus the size of circle
They're much smaller out of relative basis that coinbase
If we're looking at l1s that I think are credible like i'll say some things that I think people are going to be surprised by
Probably the best answers to this security question that I talked about from the rwa side currently come from people like avalanche
Right because if you look at how you can build subnets that's actually a legitimate solution to the problem that I just raised
Stellar and i'm sorry so a subnet can you explain just like why that is preferable over for instance like an lt on ethereum
You could have a subnet with a fully permission validator set that's docked
So the problem with the current l2 design for ethereum is you have a single sequencer
Right. So, you know, I if i'm base. I have to go as coinbase to pitch to buy nance
Hey, why don't you put your stuff on like my thing and I take all the profits? That is a hard conversation
Right an avalanche subnet because of the consortium model
Right as we think about credible neutrality
That's a term that is really under disgusting crypto because here's one form like bitcoin or ethereum on the base layer
Okay, well, let me give you another potential form of credible neutrality
Imagine an avalanche subnet where the validators which are permission so randos can't join are like the 500 largest financial companies globally
I think it's going to be hard to individually expropriate things on that chain, but that doesn't mean that any one of them can just change the rules
Right and so those sorts of consortium or consensus models have been very underexplored in blockchain
But have been incredibly successful in financial history
You know in advantage. I have as a business school professor is reading about that stuff
And so that's why I think about something like an avalanche subnet over a centralized sequencer
It's decentralization, but in a very different form
Right and then if you're looking at asset controls and like permissions and identity and authentication
There are people like say stellar is a good example of somebody who's actually thought about that a lot even though
Everybody likes to pretend they don't exist or if you're looking at just interdiction
Look at what mr. Mabs did with the cedus hack contra like the bibit hack on eath
So there there are people
Making very serious efforts at this and the question becomes who adopts them and where does the value occur?
All right, Austin. Well, it's always
Super interesting to chat with you. You said a number of things I didn't expect you to say
So thank you so much for sharing your thoughts on unchanged. Thank you
I I hope it was useful and maybe surprising in the good way for some
Yes, it was